originlab.com 2004-12-04

# OriginLab web site - Privacy Policy

|   |   | 

#### **OriginLab Online Privacy Policy:**

OriginLab is committed to protecting your privacy. You can visit most pages on our site without giving us any information about yourself. But sometimes we do need information to provide services that you request, and this privacy statement explains data collection and use in those situations. This privacy statement only applies to OriginLab.com; it does not apply to other online or offline OriginLab sites, products or services. Please read the complete OriginLab.com privacy statement. 

**Collection of personal information**

We will ask you when we need information that personally identifies you (personal information) or allows us to contact you. Generally, this information is requested when you are downloading a demo of our products, signing up for an event or training, or when purchasing and/or registering OriginLab products. Personal information collected by OriginLab.com often is limited to e-mail address, language, country or location, but may include other information when needed to provide a service you requested. 

For example: If you choose a service or transaction that requires payment, such as making a purchase in the Store area of the Web site, we will request personal information necessary for billing and/or shipping, such as: name, address, telephone number, and credit card number. 

When you buy and install a new product, we may ask you to register your purchase electronically. We keep this registration information on file with any information you've already given us on previous visits to our Web site. 

OriginLab also collects certain information about your computer hardware and software. This information may include: your IP address, browser type, operating system, domain name, access times and referring Web site addresses. This information is used for the operation of the service, to maintain quality of the service, and to provide general statistics regarding use of OriginLab.com. 

**Use of your Personal Information**

We use your personal information for the following purposes:  

  * To ensure our site is relevant to your needs. 
  * To deliver services, such as newsletters, events, training or software, that you request or purchase. 
  * To help us create and publish content most relevant to you. 
  * To alert you to product upgrades, special offers, updated information and other new services from OriginLab, if you so request. 
  * To allow you access to limited-entry areas of our site as appropriate. 

We will merge site-visitation data with anonymous demographic information for research purposes, and we may use this information in aggregate to provide more relevant content. In some limited-entry sections of OriginLab.com, with your approval, we will combine site-visitation data with your personal information in order to provide you with personalized content. If you decline permission, we will not provide you the personalized service and won’t merge your personal information with site-visitation data.

We occasionally hire other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, mailing and sending postal mail and processing event registration. We will only provide those companies the information they need to deliver the service, and they are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose.

OriginLab may disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on OriginLab or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of OriginLab and its family of Web sites, or (c) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of OriginLab employees, users of OriginLab products or services, or members of the public.

Your information may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which OriginLab or its affiliates, subsidiaries or agents maintain facilities, and by using this site, you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country. OriginLab abides by the safe harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union.

**Control of your Personal Information**

When you register, or otherwise give us personal information, OriginLab.com will not share that information with third parties without your permission, other than for the limited exceptions already listed. It will only be used for the purposes stated above. 

Registering also allows you to tell us how or whether you want OriginLab.com to communicate with you. After registering, go to the Profile Center and establish your preferences in the Contact Options sections. There, you can decide what information you want to receive and how you want to receive it. Or you can tell us not to contact you by removing check marks from the contact option boxes. If you buy software through OriginLab.com, and do not want to receive such information, do not check the box on the Checkout page (or on other pages where personal information is collected) which says: Yes, I would like to receive other offers through shop.OriginLab.com.

OriginLab.com may send out periodic e-mails informing you of technical service or security issues related to a product or service you requested, or confirming you requested a product or service. You will not be able to choose to unsubscribe to these mailings, as they are considered an essential part of the service you have chosen.

**Access to your personal information**

We will provide you with the means to ensure that your personal information is correct and current.

If you register on a OriginLab.com or subscribe to a newsletter, you can review and edit your personal information at the Profile Center. 

At the Profile Center you can: 

  * View and edit personal information you have already given us at OriginLab.com. 
  * In addition, your Customer Information resides on a secure server that only selected OriginLab personnel and contractors have access to via password.
  * Tell us whether you want OriginLab.com to send you marketing information. 
  * Choose whether you want third parties to send you their offers by postal mail.
  * Subscribe, or cancel subscriptions, to newsletters about our services and products. 

Some services offered on OriginLab.com may collect information that is not accessible via the Profile Center. However, in such cases, you can access your personal information by contacting OriginLab.com as described at the bottom of this statement, or through alternative means of access described by the service. For example, if you buy software through OriginLab.com, you can review and edit your personal information by contacting one of our Customer Service representatives Monday through Friday, between the hours of 8 a.m. and 6 p.m. ET at 1-413-586-2013. 

**Security of your Personal Information**

OriginLab.com is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use or disclosure. For example, we store the personal information you provide in computer servers with limited access that are located in controlled facilities. When we transmit sensitive information (such as a credit card number) over the internet, we protect it through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol. 

**Protection of Children's Personal Information**

OriginLab.com is a general audience site and does not knowingly collect any personal information from children.

**Use of cookies**

When someone visits the site, a cookie is placed on the customer's machine (if the customer accepts cookies) or is read if the customer has visited the site previously. One use of cookies is to assist in the collection of the site visitation statistics described above.

We also use cookies to collect information on which newsletter links are clicked by customers. This information is used to ensure we are sending information customers want to read. It is collected in aggregate form and never linked with your personal information.

Web beacons, also known as clear gif technology, or action tags, may be used to assist in delivering the cookie on our site. This technology tells us how many visitors clicked on key elements (such as links or graphics) on a OriginLab.com Web page. We do not use this technology to access your personally identifiable information on OriginLab.com; it is a tool we use to compile aggregated statistics about OriginLab.com Web site usage. We may share aggregated site statistics with partner companies but do not allow other companies to place clear gifs on our sites.

If you choose to not have your browser accept cookies from the OriginLab.com Web site, you will be able to view the text on the screens, however you will not experience a personalized visit nor will you be able to subscribe to the service offerings on the site.

Questions about cookies? Read more.....

When you visit **OriginLab.com** , you can surf the site anonymously and access important information without revealing your identity. In order to improve our site, we use "cookies" to track your visit. A cookie is small amount of data that is transferred to your browser by a Web server and can only be read by the server that gave it to you. It functions as your identification card, recording your passwords, purchases, and preferences. It cannot be executed as code or deliver viruses. Most browsers are initially set to accept cookies. You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether or not to accept it. (For some Web pages that require an authorization, cookies are not optional. Users choosing not to accept cookies will probably not be able to access those pages.) While OriginLab uses cookies to track your visit to **OriginLab.com** , and our Web servers automatically log the IP/Internet address of your computer, this information does not identify you personally and you remain anonymous unless you have otherwise provided OriginLab with personal information.

**TRUSTe Certification**

OriginLab.com is a member of the TRUSTe Privacy Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to build trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. Because OriginLab.com wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, we have agreed to publish our information practices and have our privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. 

**Enforcement of this Privacy Statement**

If you have questions regarding this statement, you should first contact OriginLab.com by e-mail. If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact TRUSTe at their [Web site](http://www.truste.org/users/users_watchdog.html). TRUSTe will serve as a liaison with OriginLab.com to resolve your concerns. 

**Changes to this Statement**

OriginLab.com will occasionally update this privacy statement. When we do, we will also revise the "last updated" date at the top of the privacy statement. For material changes to this statement, OriginLab.com will notify you by placing prominent notice on the Web site. 

**Contact Information**

OriginLab welcomes your comments regarding this privacy statement, please contact us by e-mail, or postal mail. 

OriginLab Corporation  
One Roundhouse Plaza  
Northampton, MA 01060
